Guide to the John Vance Lauderdale Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Scrapbooks, 1850-1917; Series I; 6; (16 boxes)
  - VOLUME VII, 1881-1885
    - p. 6-10, 1881 Nov-Dec (Box 7, Folder 275)
    - p. 11-15, 1881 Dec (Box 8, Folder 276)
    - p. 16-20, 1882 Jan-Feb (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - p. 21-27, 1882 Feb (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - p. 28-32, 1882 Mar (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - p. 33-38, 1882 Apr (Box 8, Folder 280)
    - p. 39-43, 1882 May-Jun (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - p. 44-49, 1882 Jun-Jul (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - p. 49-53, 1882 Jul-Aug (Box 8, Folder 283)
    - p. 54-57, 1882 Aug-Sep (Box 8, Folder 284)
    - p. 58-61, 1882 Sep (Box 8, Folder 285)
    - p. 62-68, 1882 Oct-Nov (Box 8, Folder 286)
    - p. 69-72, 1882 Nov-Dec (Box 8, Folder 287)
    - p. 73-76, 1882 Dec (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - p. 77-81, 1883 Jan-Feb (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - p. 82-84, 1883 Feb-Mar (Box 8, Folder 290)
    - p. 85-87, 1883 Mar (Box 8, Folder 291)
    - p. 88-92, 1883 Apr-May (Box 8, Folder 292)
    - p. 93-98, 1883 May-Jun (Box 8, Folder 293)
    - p. 99-102, 1883 Jun (Box 8, Folder 294)
    - p. 103-108, 1883 Jul-Aug (Box 8, Folder 295)
    - p. 109-115, 1883 Aug-Sep (Box 8, Folder 296)
    - p. 116-121, 1883 Oct-Nov (Box 8, Folder 297)
    - p. 122-129, 1883 Nov-Dec (Box 8, Folder 298)
    - p. 130-139, 1883 Dec (Box 8, Folder 299-301)
    - p. 140-144, 1884 Jan (Box 8, Folder 302)
    - p. 145-147, 1884 Jan-Feb (Box 8, Folder 303)
    - p. 148-155, 1884 Feb (Box 8, Folder 304)
    - p. 156-163, 1884 Feb-Mar (Box 8, Folder 305)
    - p. 164-172, 1884 Mar-May (Box 8, Folder 306)
    - p. 173-180, 1884 May (Box 8, Folder 307)
    - p. 181-185, 1884 Jun 1-9 (Box 8, Folder 308-09)
    - p. 186-193, 1884 Jun-Jul (Box 8, Folder 310)
    - p. 194-200, 1884 Jul-Aug (Box 8, Folder 311)
    - p. 201-206, 1884 Aug (Box 9, Folder 312)
    - p. 207-211, 1884 Sep (Box 9, Folder 313)
    - p. 212-214, 1884 Sep-Oct (Box 9, Folder 314)
    - p. 215-221, 1884 Oct (Box 9, Folder 315)
    - p. 222-228, 1884 Nov (Box 9, Folder 316)
    - p. 229-235, 1884 Dec (Box 9, Folder 317)
    - p. 236-239, 1885 Jan-Feb (Box 9, Folder 318)
    - p. 240-243, 1885 Feb (Box 9, Folder 319)
    - p. 244-248, 1885 Mar-Apr (Box 9, Folder 320)
    - p. 249-253, 1885 Apr-May (Box 9, Folder 321)
  - VOLUME VIII, 1885-1889
    - Index (Box 9, Folder 322)
    - p. 1-4, 1885 May (Box 9, Folder 323)
    - p. 5-7, 1885 Jun (Box 9, Folder 324)
    - p. 8-10, 1885 Jun-Jul (Box 9, Folder 325)
    - p. 11-14, 1885 Jul-Aug (Box 9, Folder 326)
    - p. 15-21, 1885 Aug-Sep (Box 9, Folder 327)
    - p. 22-23, 1885 Sep (Box 9, Folder 328)
    - p. 24-29, 1885 Sep-Oct (Box 9, Folder 329)
    - p. 30-36, 1885 Oct (Box 9, Folder 330-31)
    - p. 37-41, 1885 Nov-Dec (Box 9, Folder 332)
    - p. 42-46, 1885 Dec (Box 9, Folder 333)
    - p. 47-52, 1886 Jan (Box 9, Folder 334)
    - p. 53-57, 1886 Feb (Box 9, Folder 335)
    - p. 58-62, 1886 Mar-Apr (Box 9, Folder 336)
    - p. 63-66, 1886 Apr-May (Box 9, Folder 337)
    - p. 67-72, 1886 May-Jun (Box 9, Folder 338)
    - p. 73-82, 1886 Jun (Box 9, Folder 339-40)
    - p. 83-88, 1886 Jul (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - p. 90-92, 1886 Aug (Box 9, Folder 342)
    - p. 93-95, 1886 Aug-Sep (Box 9, Folder 343)
    - p. 96-98, 1886 Sep-Oct (Box 9, Folder 344)
    - p. 99-106, 1886 Oct (Box 9, Folder 345)
    - p. 107-108, 1886 Nov-Dec (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - p. 109-111, 1886 Dec (Box 9, Folder 347)
    - p. 112-113, 1887 Jan (Box 9, Folder 348)
    - p. 114-117, 1887 Jan-Feb (Box 9, Folder 349)
    - p. 118-122, 1887 Feb-Mar (Box 9, Folder 350)
    - p. 123-126, 1887 Mar-Apr (Box 9, Folder 351)
    - p. 127-130, 1887 Apr (Box 9, Folder 352)
    - p. 131-135, 1887 May-Jun (Box 9, Folder 353-54)
    - p. 136-140, 1887 Jun-Jul (Box 10, Folder 355)
    - p. 141-144, 1887 Jul (Box 10, Folder 356)
    - p. 145-149, 1887 Aug-Sep (Box 10, Folder 357)
    - p. 150-153, 1887 Sep-Oct (Box 10, Folder 358)
    - p. 154-158, 1887 Oct-Nov (Box 10, Folder 359)
    - p. 159-162, 1887 Nov-Dec (Box 10, Folder 360)
    - p. 163-166, 1887 Dec (Box 10, Folder 361)
    - p. 167-170, 1888 Jan-Feb (Box 10, Folder 362)
    - p. 171-179, 1888 Feb-Mar (Box 10, Folder 363)
    - p. 180-184, 1888 Mar (Box 10, Folder 364)
    - p. 185-188, 1888 Apr-May (Box 10, Folder 365)
    - p. 189-190, 1888 May (Box 10, Folder 366)
    - p. 191-194, 1888 May-Jun (Box 10, Folder 367)
    - p. 195-198, 1888 Jun (Box 10, Folder 368)
    - p. 199-203, 1888 Jul-Aug (Box 10, Folder 369)
    - p. 204-207, 1888 Aug-Sep (Box 10, Folder 370)
    - p. 208-212, 1888 Sep (Box 10, Folder 371)
    - p. 213-218, 1888 Oct-Nov (Box 10, Folder 372)
    - p. 219-223, 1888 Nov-Dec (Box 10, Folder 373)
    - p. 224-225, 1888 Dec (Box 10, Folder 374)
    - p. 226-228, 1888 Dec-1889 Jan (Box 10, Folder 375)
    - p. 229-232, 1889 Jan-Feb (Box 10, Folder 376)
    - p. 233-235, 1889 Feb (Box 10, Folder 377)
    - p. 236-238, 1889 Feb (Box 10, Folder 378)
      Includes letter from W. Von Steeruwitz dated 1890 Mar 3
  - VOLUME IX, 1889-1892
    - Index (Box 10, Folder 379)
    - p. 1-7, 1889 Mar-May (Box 10, Folder 380)
    - p. 8-13, 1889 May-Jun (Box 10, Folder 381)
    - p. 14-18, 1889 Jun (Box 10, Folder 382)
    - p. 19-20, 1889 Jul (Box 10, Folder 383)
    - p. 21-23, 1889 Jul-Aug (Box 10, Folder 384)
    - p. 24-28, 1889 Aug-Sep (Box 10, Folder 385)
    - p. 29-33, 1889 Sep-Oct (Box 10, Folder 386)
    - p. 34-37, 1889 Oct-Nov (Box 10, Folder 387)
    - p. 38-41, 1889 Nov (Box 10, Folder 388)
    - p. 42-46, 1889 Dec (Box 10, Folder 389)
    - p. 47-53, 1890 Jan-Feb (Box 10, Folder 390)
    - p. 54-58, 1890 Feb-Mar (Box 10, Folder 391)
    - p. 59-66, 1890 Mar-Apr (Box 10, Folder 392)
    - p. 67-70, 1890 Apr (Box 10, Folder 393)
    - p. 71-72, 1890 Apr (Box 10, Folder 394)
      Includes two letters dated 1890 Jan 4 amd 1889 Aug 2 regarding Lauderdale's ties to the Christian Association of Mexico City
    - p. 73-79, 1890 May (Box 11, Folder 395)
    - p. 80-82, 1890 Jun-Jul (Box 11, Folder 396)
    - p. 83-90, 1890 Jul (Box 11, Folder 397-98)
    - p. 91-95, 1890 Aug-Sep (Box 11, Folder 399)
    - p. 96-98, 1890 Sep-Oct (Box 11, Folder 400)
    - p. 99-101, 1890 Oct-Nov (Box 11, Folder 401)
    - p. 102, 104, 1890 Nov (Box 11, Folder 402)
    - p. 105-109, 1890 Dec (Box 11, Folder 403)
    - p. 110, 1891 Jan 1-10 (Box 11, Folder 404)
    - p. 111-118, 1891 Jan 12-20 (Box 11, Folder 405)
    - p. 119-130, 1891 Jan 21-31 (Box 11, Folder 406)
    - p. 131-139, 1891 Feb 1-8 (Box 11, Folder 407)
    - p. 140-148, 1891 Feb 9-18 (Box 11, Folder 408)
    - p. 149-157, 1891 Feb 19-28 (Box 11, Folder 409)
    - p. 158-163, 1891 Mar (Box 11, Folder 410)
    - p. 164-169, 1891 Apr-May (Box 11, Folder 411)
    - p. 170-177, 1891 May (Box 11, Folder 412)
    - p. 178-183, 1891 Jun-Jul (Box 11, Folder 413)
    - p. 184-189, 1891 Jul-Aug (Box 11, Folder 414)
    - p. 190-193, 1891 Aug (Box 11, Folder 415)
    - p. 194-199, 1891 Aug-Sep (Box 11, Folder 416)
    - p. 200-203, 1891 Sep-Oct (Box 11, Folder 417)
    - p. 204-206, 1891 Oct (Box 11, Folder 418)
    - p. 207-211, 1891 Nov-Dec (Box 11, Folder 419)
    - p. 212-215, 1891 Dec (Box 11, Folder 420)
    - p. 216-222, 1892 Jan (Box 11, Folder 421)
    - p. 223-227, 1892 Feb-Mar (Box 11, Folder 422)
    - p. 228-231, 1892 Mar-Apr (Box 11, Folder 423)
    - p. 232-235, 1892 Apr (Box 11, Folder 424)
    - p. 236-240, 1892 May-Jun (Box 11, Folder 425)
    - p. 241-249, 1892 Jun-Nov (Box 11, Folder 426)
  - VOLUME X, 1892-1895
    - Index (Box 11, Folder 427)
    - p. 1-4, 1892 Jul (Box 11, Folder 428)
    - p. 5-11, 1892 Aug-Sep (Box 11, Folder 429)
    - p. 12-15, 1892 Sep (Box 12, Folder 430)
    - p. 16-20, 1892 Oct-Nov (Box 12, Folder 431)
    - p. 21-26, 1892 Nov-Dec (Box 12, Folder 432)
    - p. 27-33, 1892 Dec (Box 12, Folder 433)
    - p. 34-39, 1893 Jan-Feb (Box 12, Folder 434)
    - p. 40-43, 1893 Feb-Mar (Box 12, Folder 435)
    - p. 44-47, 1893 Mar-Apr (Box 12, Folder 436)
    - p. 48-51, 1893 Apr (Box 12, Folder 437)
    - p. 52-58, 1893 May-Jun (Box 12, Folder 438)
    - p. 59-65, 1893 Jun-Jul (Box 12, Folder 439)
    - p. 66-75, 1893 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 440)
    - p. 80-85, 1893 Jul-Sep (Box 12, Folder 441)
    - p. 86-92, 1893 Sep-Oct (Box 12, Folder 442)
    - p. 93-98, 1893 Oct-Nov (Box 12, Folder 443)
    - p. 99-104, 1893 Nov-Dec (Box 12, Folder 444)
    - p. 105-117, 1893 Dec-1894 Jan (Box 12, Folder 445)
    - p. 118-123, 1894 Jan (Box 12, Folder 446)
    - p. 124-132, 1894 Jan (Box 12, Folder 447)
    - p. 133-136, 1894 Feb-Mar (Box 12, Folder 448)
    - p. 137-144, 1894 Mar-Apr (Box 12, Folder 449)
    - p. 145-148, 1894 Apr (Box 12, Folder 450)
    - p. 149-158, 1894 May-Jun (Box 12, Folder 451)
    - p. 159-170, 1894 Jun-Jul (Box 12, Folder 452)
    - p. 171-180, 1894 Jul (Box 12, Folder 453-56)
    - p. 181-184, 1894 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 457)
    - p. 185-190, 1894 Aug (Box 12, Folder 458)
    - p. 191-196, 1894 Sep-Oct (Box 12, Folder 459)
    - p. 197-200, 1894 Oct-Nov (Box 12, Folder 460)
    - p. 201-212, 1894 Nov-Dec (Box 12, Folder 461)
    - p. 213-220, 1894-1895 (Box 12, Folder 462)
    - p. 221-226, 1895 Feb-Mar (Box 12, Folder 463)
    - p. 227-234, 1895 Mar-Apr (Box 12, Folder 464)
    - p. 235-240, 1895 Apr-May (Box 12, Folder 465)
    - p. 241-246, 1895 May-Jun (Box 12, Folder 466)
  - VOLUME XI, 1895-1897
    - Index (Box 13, Folder 467)
    - p. 1-6, 1895 Jun-Aug (Box 13, Folder 468)
    - p. 7-11, 1895 Aug-Sep (Box 13, Folder 469)
    - p. 12-16, 1895 Sep-Oct (Box 13, Folder 470)
    - p. 17-21, 1895 Oct-Dec (Box 13, Folder 471)
    - p. 21-23, 1895 Dec (Box 13, Folder 472)
    - p. 24-30, 1895 Jan-Mar (Box 13, Folder 473)
    - p. 31-33, 1895 Mar-Apr (Box 13, Folder 474)
    - p. 34-36, 1895 Apr-May (Box 13, Folder 475)
    - p. 37-39, 1895 May-Jun (Box 13, Folder 476)
    - p. 40-43, 1896 Jun-Jul (Box 13, Folder 477)
    - p. 44-47, 1896 Jul-Aug (Box 13, Folder 478)
    - p. 48-53, 1896 Aug-Sep (Box 13, Folder 479)
    - p. 54-57, 1896 Sep-Oct (Box 13, Folder 480)
    - p. 58-65, 1896 Oct (Box 13, Folder 481)
    - p. 66-70, 1896 Oct-Nov (Box 13, Folder 482)
    - p. 71-79, 1896 Nov (Box 13, Folder 483)
    - p. 80-101, 1896 Nov-Dec (Box 13, Folder 484-89)
    - p. 102-111, 1897 Jan (Box 13, Folder 490)
    - p. 112-119, 1897 Jan-Feb (Box 14, Folder 491)
    - p. 120-136, 1897 Feb (Box 14, Folder 492-95)
    - p. 137-146, 1897 Mar (Box 14, Folder 496)
    - p. 147-150, 1897 Mar (Box 14, Folder 497)
  - VOLUME XII, 1897-1904
    - Index (Box 14, Folder 498)
    - p. 1-8, 1897 Apr (Box 14, Folder 499)
    - p. 9-14, 1897 Apr-May (Box 14, Folder 500)
    - p. 15-17, 1897 May-Jun (Box 14, Folder 501)
    - p. 18-24, 1897 Jun-Jul (Box 14, Folder 502)
    - p. 25-29, 1897 Jul-Aug (Box 14, Folder 503)
    - p. 30-34, 1897 Aug-Sep (Box 14, Folder 504)
    - p. 35-37, 1897 Sep-Dec (Box 14, Folder 505)
    - p. 37-38, 1898 Jan-May (Box 14, Folder 506)
    - p. 39, 1898 Apr-Jul (Box 14, Folder 507)
    - p. 40-41, 1898 Jul-Aug (Box 14, Folder 508)
    - p. 42-46, 1898 Aug-Sep (Box 14, Folder 509)
    - p. 47-52, 1898 Sep-Oct (Box 14, Folder 510)
    - p. 53-58, 1898-1901 (Box 14, Folder 511)
    - p. 59-64, 66-69, 1899-1902 (Box 14, Folder 512)
    - p. 70-73, 1902 Jul-Nov (Box 14, Folder 513)
    - p. 75-76, 1903 Jan-Feb (Box 14, Folder 514)
    - p. 77, 1903, 1905 (Box 14, Folder 515)
    - p. 78, 1899 Feb-Dec (Box 15, Folder 516)
    - p. 79-80, 1899-1900 (Box 15, Folder 517)
    - p. 81-85, 1901-1902 (Box 15, Folder 518)
    - p. 86-93, 1902-1903 (Box 15, Folder 519)
    - p. 93.5, 1903 (Box 15, Folder 520)
    - p. 94-98, 100, 1903 Apr-Jun (Box 15, Folder 521)
    - p. 101-112, 1903 Jul (Box 15, Folder 522-23)
    - p. 113-117, 1903 Aug (Box 15, Folder 524)
    - p. 118-122, 1903 Aug-Dec (Box 15, Folder 525)
    - p. 123-134, 1903 Sep-Oct (Box 15, Folder 526)
      Includes correspondence between Lauderdale and his sister from 1860 to 1862
    - p. 135-147, 1863-1903 (Box 15, Folder 527)
    - p. 148-151, 1903 Nov-Dec (Box 15, Folder 528)
    - p. 160-166, 1904 Jan-Mar (Box 15, Folder 529)
    - p. 167-172, 1904 Apr-Jun (Box 15, Folder 530)
  - VOLUME XIII, 1904-1917
    - Index (Box 15, Folder 531)
    - p. 1-2, 4-8, 1904 Nov-Dec (Box 15, Folder 532-33)
    - p. 9, 11-18, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 534-36)
    - p. 19-35, 1906 (Box 16, Folder 537-39)
    - p. 36-39, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 540)
    - p. 40-43, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 541)
    - p. 44-47, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - p. 48-50, 52, 1907-1908 (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - p. 53-59, 61-63, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 544-46)
    - p. 65-71, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - p. 72-73, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 548)
    - p. 76-79, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 549)
    - p. 80-85, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 550)
    - p. 86-87, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 551)
    - p. 88-91, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 552)
    - p. 92-93, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 553)
    - p. 94-99, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 554)
    - p. 100-102, 1913, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 555)
    - p. 103-109, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 556)
    - p. 110-128, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 557-59)
    - Unpaginated programs and invitations, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 560)
- Family Papers, 1913-1931; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Genealogical material, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 561)
  - LAUDERDALE, JOHN VANCE
    - Death certificate (certified copy), 1931 Jan 23 (Box 16, Folder 562)
    - Obituaries, 1931 Jan (Box 16, Folder 563)
    - Last Will and Testament, typed, 1922 May 31 (Box 16, Folder 564)
  - LAUDERDALE, JOSEPHINE LANE
    - Obituaries and church service bulletin, 1913, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 565)
- Lantern Slides, 1882-1996; Series III; 2.5; (2 boxes)
  - Lantern slides, c. 1882-96 (Box 17)
  - Lantern slides, c. 1882-96 (Box 18)
- Oversize, 1.75; (1 box) + 5 broadside folders
  - Vance, Samuel: land grant (VOLUME XII), 1838 Sep 5 (Box 19, Folder 566)
    Signed by Martin Van Buren
  - Meteorological observations (VOLUME III), 1868 (Box 20 (Broadside), Folder 567)
  - Correspondence (VOLUME VII), 1884 Mar-Apr (Box 19, Folder 568)
  - Map of Chicago World's Fair (VOLUME X), 1893 (Box 21 (Broadside), Folder 569)
  - Broadside for public auction at Fort Omaha, Neb. (VOLUME XI), 1896 (Box 19, Folder 570)
  - Brooklyn Young Men's Christian Association: seating arrangements (VOLUME XII), 1902 Nov 6 (Box 19, Folder 571)
  - The Manse Gazette, 1904 Jun 29 (Box 19, Folder 572)
  - Society of the Genesee: Annual dinner seating arrangements (VOLUME XII), 1905 Feb 7 (Box 19, Folder 573)
  - Society of the Genesee: Annual dinner seating arrangements (VOLUME XII), 1908 Feb 8 (Box 19, Folder 574)
  - "Forest Park University," The Continent (VOLUME IX), 1912 May 23 (Box 19, Folder 575)
  - Program for Al. G. Field's Famous- American Minstrels and a signed watercolor of a rose (VOLUME IX), n.d., [1928?] (Box 19, Folder 576)
  - Newspaper clipping (VOLUME XIII), n.y. Aug 23 (Box 19, Folder 577)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings (VOLUMES X and XII) (Box 22 (Broadside), Folder 578)
  - Correspondence, clippings and printed ephemera (VOLUME XI), 1867-1901, n.d. (Box 23 (Broadside), Folder 579)
  - Magazine clippings, train schedules, and California hotel brochures (VOLUME XI) (Box 24 (Broadside), Folder 580)
  - p. 92 (VOLUME XIII), 1911 (Box 19, Folder 581)
  - Unpaginated programs and invitations (VOLUME XIII), 1917 (Box 19, Folder 582)